Guide to the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Spain Serials TAM.783
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Spain Serials
1935-2003
1936-1989
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
TAM.783
1.6 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes and 1 flat box
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Spain Serials contains over 50 titles published in and about Spain between 1935 and 2003. The majority of the serials are about the Spanish Civil War. The bulk of the collection dates from the 1930s and the 1980s.
Arrangement
Serials in this collection are arranged alphabetically by title.
Conditions Governing Access
Open to users without restriction.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
This collection combines serials relating to Spain drawn from two discrete groups of material held by the Tamiment Library. The first was a partially inventoried backlog of serials, received by the library through donations, subscriptions, and in archival collections. The second group consisted of around 1,700 serials, newspapers, and magazines, organized by title as an artificial collection, referred to as Periodicals.001 or Boxed Newspapers. This material was combined, inventoried, and arranged and described in subject-based categories in 2017. The accession number related to this collection is 2017.049.
Scope and Contents
The Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives Collection of Spain Serials contains over 50 titles published in Spain and about Spain between 1935 and 2003. The majority of the serials are about the Spanish Civil War. The bulk of the collection dates from the 1930s to the 1980s. The serials on the Spanish Civil War include titles published during the war between 1936 and 1939, mainly by Republican and Communist groups, and in the 1960s through 1980s by and about veterans of the war. Other topics include communism, labor, and national politics in Spain in the 20th century. The majority of the serials were published in Spain, with other serials published in France, Italy, Sweden, the United Kingdom, and the United States.
Spain -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Periodicals.; Serials (publications); Spain -- Politics and government -- 20th century.
- Accion Republicana: Accion Republicana, Madrid, Spain, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Acero / Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. 5. Cuerpo.: El Cuerpo, Spain, 1938 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- AMI: Periodico del Servicio Sanitario Internacional (B.I.): Servicio Sanitario Internacional (B.I.), Madrid, Spain, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- Boletin de Educacion: Ministerio de Instruccion Publica y Bellas Artes, Valencia, Spain, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 12-31)
- Boletin de Informacion: Partido Comunista Frances, 1964-1968 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Boletin de Informacion del F.R.A.P.: Agencia de Prensa España Popular (A.P.E.P.), 1971 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- Bulletin of the Spanish Workers' Defence Committee: Spanish Workers' Defence Committee, London, UK, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Catalonian Correspondence: Catalonian Committee of New York, New York, NY, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- Coleccion Los Suplementos: Cuadernos para el Dialogo, Madrid, Spain, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Cuadernos Bibliograficos de la Guerra de España: Universidad de Madrid, Madrid, Spain, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Ekintza Zuzena: Ediciones E.Z., Bilbao, Spain, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Enciclopedic: Centre de Documentacio Historico, Barcelona, Spain, 2000-2002 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Enlace: D.N.S. Vicesecretaria Nacional de Ordenacion Social, Madrid, Spain, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- España: Imprimerie Cooperative Etoile, Paris, France, 1939 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- España: Cenit, Toulouse, France, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- España Libre: Confederated Spanish Societies of the United States, New York, NY, 1940-1977 (Box 1, Folder 5-6)
- España Popular, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Estampa: Madrid, Spain, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Etcetera: Correspondencia de la Guerra Social: Etcetera, Barcelona, Spain, 1984-1990 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Euskadi Sioux: San Sebastian, Spain, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Extra: Prensa Periodica, Madrid, Spain, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Fighting Call: Freedom Group/Anti-Parliamentary Communist Federation, London, UK/Glasgow, Scotland, 1936 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- For Ett Fritt Spanien: Svenska Spanienfrivilligas Kamratforening, Stockholm, Sweden, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Frente Rojo: Partido Comunista, Valencia, Spain, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Guerra Espanola: Cronica de la Guerra Espanola, Spain, Undated (Box 3, Folder 1-3)
- Hacer: Madrid, Spain, 1990 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- La Aurora: Partido Obrero Revolucionario de España, Spain, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- La Union del Pueblo: Comite Central del Partido del Trabajo de España, Spain, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- La Voz de los Olvidados: L'Association d'Anciens Combattants et Victimes de Guerre de la Republique Espagnole, Perpignan, France, 1982 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Laberintos: Generalitat Valenciana, Valencia, Spain, 2002 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Madrid en Pie!: Comite de Madrid del Movimiento Comunista de España, Madrid, Spain, 1974-1977 (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Mañana: Paris, France, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- News Bulletin from the National Office of the JAFRC: Joint Anti-Fascist Refugee Committee, New York, NY, 1948-1949 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Ocear: Ministerio del Trabajo y Asistencia Social, 1937 (Box 1, Folder 1-13)
- Pensamientos: El Sembrador, Spain, Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Per la Libertà della Spagna: Associazione Italiana Combattenti Volontari Antifascisti di Spagna, Rome, Italy, 1976-1981 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Politica, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Politica: Revista Republicana, Madrid, Spain, 1999-2000 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Porvenir, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- Rebelion: Colectivo Antimilitarista pro Insumision, Granada, Spain, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- Reconquista, 1938 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Revista Iberoamericana de Autogestión y Acción Comunal: Altalena Editores, Madrid, Spain, 1983 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Semaforo: Valencia, Spain, 1937 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- Spain: Spanish War Events, New York, NY, 1938-1939 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Spanish Echo: American Publicity Committee on Spain, New York, NY, 1935 (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Spanish Republic: Alianza Espanola por un Mundo Libre, New York, NY, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Spanish Revolution: Workers' Party of Marxist Unification, Barcelona, Spain, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Spanish Revolution: Greenwood Reprint Corporation, New York, NY, 1968 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Spanish Revolution: Party of Marxist Unification, Barcelona, Spain, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Unidad y Lucha en el Metal: Las Comisiones Oberas del Ramo del Metal de la Coordinatora Local de Barcelona, Barcelona, Spain, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Union Sindical Texto Integro del Estatuto de los Trabajadores: Pleno de las Cortes Generales, Madrid, Spain, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- UPA: Agency of Information, Madrid, Spain, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Visions de Guerra i de Reraguardia: Història Gràfica de la Revolució: Barcelona, Spain, Undated (Box 4, Folder 9-10)
- Zona Alliberada: l'Assemblea de Joves de Gracia, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 11)